#### **BRADLEY COONEY**

Phone: +44 777 3899134

Email: <a href="mailto:bradleyh.cooney@gmail.com">bradleyh.cooney@gmail.com</a>
Web: <a href="mailto:bradleyh.cooney@gmail.com">bradleyh.cooney@gmail.com</a>

#### **Profile**

I am a highly competent Digital Producer with strong experience in managing client physical and digital events from the technical, attendee experience, content and speaker perspective.

Behind this experience sits 6 years of successfully leading and delivering client projects, budgets up to \$3m and managing teams of varying degrees of skill and seniority.

With the pandemic disrupting the events industry, I took advantage of the opportunity to pursue the Diploma in Full-Stack Development course with Code Institute, building on previous code knowledge.

Whilst not holding a professional position, the self-education over the past 3 years has provided extensive exposure to best practice in UX & UI design, as well as HTML5, CSS3 and PHP languages.

With the Diploma strengthening these skills and adding further languages and frameworks to my skillset, I am keen to apply this knowledge in a professional setting, and continue learning from experienced peers and senior developers.

#### Skills

### Technical

HTML5
CSS3
Python
Django
MongoDB
MySQL
Codelgniter
Javascript

#### Other

Project Management Event Production Content Production Adobe Illustrator Adobe XD Budget Management Team Leadership



### **Employment History**

### 2020 - Present | Digital Producer, Events Agency

Lead and oversee virtual event projects, whilst relationships with platform nurturina technology suppliers, enabling colleagues to accurately recommend suitable the most platforms tools for and digital projects.

The role also requires me to lead developers and designers in creating UX & UI design of bespoke platforms and presenting the functionality and limitations to clients.

I then manage the development process and oversee device, browser and user experience testing with the wider team and client IT departments.

If the project focus is on content delivery, then I work alongside our internal Technical Department to evaluate video playback and remote contributor options, whilst managing client content and edits, before leading the delivery of the live broadcast, calling the show as required.

#### 2019 - 2020 | Producer, Events Agency

Key responsibilities for this role centered around client and team management, with a specific focus on the holistic program experience - working with our Strategy, Account and Creative Directors' to analyse a client brief, refine through further questioning, before leading the development of a thorough creative response.

After successfully pitching the proposal to the client, I would then become responsible for leading the project team of varied skill and abilities, from Senior and Junior positions, to successful execution of the event.

As line producer on various shows, my responsibility included the delivery of keynotes and sessions within an event. This required liaison with senior and C-level clientele, to ensure they delivered content to our team, as well as managing stage orientation and rehearsals for speakers.

### **Employment History**

## 2015 - 2019 | Project Manager, Events Agency

Project lead for the successful delivery of numerous programs for a variety of clients such as VMware, Microsoft, Atos and New Balance.

Core competencies within this role included the management of both Senior and Junior team members within the project team, from various departments (creative, F&B, technical, accounts, registration etc), client management and budget management up to \$3m.

Projects were managed in accordance with internal policies and procedures to ensure continuity in delivery, and would range from 80 person exclusive executive events, to partner program events up to 2,500 persons.

#### **Interests**

If not tinkering with my event community website, aside from the obvious 'socialising with friends', I find myself on spontaneous jaunts in search of coffee or decent food establishments.

To keep fit, I compete with myself in solo running and cycling stints, simply to beat my previous time, and more importantly, find coffee faster.

Whilst attempting the above, I am a serial podcast listener, predominantly in the self-improvement or educational genres. Frequent Podcasts include Tim Ferris, Syntax, Bootstrapped Web, Pat Flynn SPI and for uplifting house music, Chicane Sun:Sets, among others.

### **Education & Qualifications**

## Diploma in Full Stack Development 2021 | Code Institute

Final grade TBD, Diploma credit-rated by University of Edinburgh Napier.

# 1st Class Hons. in Events Management 2014 | University of Greenwich

First class degree in the marketing, business and project management of Events.